# **PATRICKMUTH**

Brooklyn, NY | 603-512-7131 | patrick.muth@gmail.com

Creative problem solver with a proven track record of designing highly usable, user-centered experiences. Passion for combining creativity and technology to make people's lives better.

#### **SKILLS**

Design, iterate and refine UX concepts through research, storyboards, user flows, wireframes, prototyping & user testing. Effectively communicate user experience designs to team members, stakeholders, and present to clients.

Deep knowledge and experience in Sketch, Framer, InVision and Adobe Creative Suite

Extensive experience prototyping a variety of interactive projects, including web/mobile (HTML5/CSS/Javascript/jQuery/Node.js), experiential & physical computing.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Experience Designer (Contract), Publicis Sapient

New York, NY, July 2020 to Present

 Developing user flows, information architecture and wireframes for updated user management system for a national business-focused telecommunications company

## Senior UX Designer (Contract), AKQA

New York, NY, December 2019 to April 2020

- Developed information architecture and wireframes for a design system repo for a major US hospital's new digital component library
- Created user flows and preliminary wireframes for a proof of concept for the hospital's new patient scheduling tool

## Senior Interaction Designer (Contract), frog

Brooklyn, NY, October 2019 to December 2019

 Developed wireframes, information architecture and interactive prototypes (Framer) for the digital launch of a new investment platform for a major American investment group

### UX Designer (Contract), Big Spaceship

Brooklyn, NY, September 2019 to October 2019

 Developed wireframes, user flows & competitive analyses for a national satellite radio providers website redesign, focusing on site search and customer account administration

# Senior UX Designer (Contract), Valtech

New York, NY, April 2019 to May 2019

- Led user experience on the development of a digital innovation focused concept store for a national makeup brand, creating concepts for new digital interaction for both the in-store and online experience
- Conducted in-person interviews with customers and store employees to develop insights and user journeys based on their shopping behavior

### **UX Designer, Patients & Purpose**

New York, NY, November 2016 to October 2018

- Created wireframes, user flows and functional specs for projects with multinational pharmaceutical companies including desktop and mobile web sites and mobile apps
- Participated in the execution of usability studies, creating wireframes, clickable prototypes and user interview questions
- Spearheaded ongoing research on new approaches and ideas such as chatbots, progressive registration and voice user interactions for integration into new and ongoing work streams

# Junior UX Designer, Bossa Digital

New York, NY, August 2013 to September 2016

- Designed responsive web wireframes and user flows for clients such as General Mills, Google & Target, as well as a Cannes Lion winning campaign for Coke Zero
- Created interactive prototypes of mobile designs for clients such as McDonalds, Coke Zero & Airbnb using Framer, InVision & Pixate

#### **EDUCATION**

**NYU**, **Tisch School of the Arts**, **ITP**, MPS (Masters) in Interactive Telecommunications **Providence College**, B.S. in Marketing